Christopher T. Morse

Email: drb6yv@virginia.edu — Phone: (402) 326-7906 — Website: christheissmorse.github.io

Professional Summary

Curious and motivated early career professional with specialized knowledge in the intersection of software engineering, machine learning, and robotics. Skilled researcher and presenter with a history of publications and awards. Extends perspective through cross-disciplinary collaboration. Resourceful problem solver with an M.S. in Computer Science initiating career in robot software engineering.

EDUCATION

University of Virginia M.S. in Computer Science

Charlottesville, VA

May 2023

GPA: 4.00 / 4.00

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities B.A. in Computer Science, Minor in Music

Minneapolis, MN May 2021

GPA: 3.91 / 4.00

Work EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, University of Virginia

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

CS 4501: Robotics for Software Engineers

CS 1010: Introduction to Information Technology

- Developed teaching materials for robot control, localization, sensing, and ROS system design.
- Designed and led engaging laboratory sections for 50+ students.

Research Assistant, University of Virginia

Aug. 2021 - Dec. 2022

Leading Engineering for Safe Software (LESS) Laboratory

- Created a novel method for inferring spatial properties from robot data.
 - Built a pipeline to approximate scene coverage for AV perception systems.

Research Assistant, University of Minnesota

Jan. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Interactive Robotics and Vision (IRV) Laboratory

- Developed a streamlined method for paired diver image generation to combat data scarcity.
- Investigated a method for synthetic image generation to aid with data augmentation.

Teaching Assistant, University of Minnesota

Sept. 2018 - Dec. 2019

CSCI 2011: Discrete Structures of Computer Science

CSCI 1133: Intro. to Computing and Programming Concepts

Conducted laboratory sections to encourage student collaboration and participation.

REU Research Assistant, University of Nebraska

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

Nebraska Intelligent MoBile Unmanned Systems (NIMBUS) Laboratory

- Analyzed effects of hyperparameter tuning and data augmentation on UAV detection.
- Integration and testing with NVIDIA Jetson Nano.

PROJECTS

Network Packet Analysis with NLP

Spring 2023

- Created a novel command line tool to parse and query network data with NLP.
- Utilized the GPT-3 API to generate SQL queries over MySQL data tables.

VAE-Guided Testing Framework for OpenPilot

Spring 2022

- Designed and trained a VAE for manifold approximation of traffic images.
- Clustered training set images with K-Means and PCA to exploit underrepresented features.

SKILLS

Python/C++/C/SQL - Machine Learning - Robot Perception (Cameras, LiDAR) - Docker - Git

SERVICE, HONORS, AND AWARDS

• Paper Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation

Fall 2022

• UROP Research Award Recipient

Summer 2020

• 2nd Place; University of Nebraska REU Research Competition

Summer 2019

Publications

C. Morse, L. Feng, M. Dwyer, S. Elbaum, "A Framework for the Unsupervised Inference of Relations Between Sensed Object Spatial Distributions and Robot Behaviors." 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA).

M. J. Islam, C. Edge, Y. Xiao, P. Luo, M. Mehtaz, C. Morse, S. S. Enan, and J. Sattar, "Semantic Segmentation of Underwater Imagery: Dataset and Benchmark." 2020 IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).